BERK PEKER

Software Engineer

- **\ +90-533-688-3630**
- @ berkpeker94@gmail.com
- https://tr.linkedin.com/in/berk-peker-46a453108
 https://github.com/berkpeker2707
- ♀ Istanbul, Turkey

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 4 years of experience in JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose, Electron, React, React Native, Python, Pandas.

Maintained and development an order processor programmed in Python and shipping rate calculator. Developed an app in React Native for employee management. Developed and maintained an electron.js app for product design automation. Developed a social media application for pets with React Native. Developed a matching app with MERN stack, used microservice structures for backend and hosted it on AWS then changed it to Azure; hosted client side on Vercel.

Worked on various projects and with different goals, consequently looking forward to use my React Native and my backend development skills with new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

MOCUK Design

Developed & maintaned *employee management and customer service system* with React Native project, *order processing and management projects* with Python, *product designing project* with Electron, Illustrator & Photoshop Script, *Slack bot* for saving and removing data to external source.

- mocukApp
 - Project Link: https://github.com/berkpeker2707/mocukApp
- SlackGooglesheetAppscript

Project Link:

https://github.com/berkpeker2707/SlackGooglesheetAppscript

- Automation
- Example Link: https://youtu.be/qX8m59BSWUI
- Shipzon is an order process tool, pulls order data from Shipstation (Amazon & ETSY order data stored data), seperates store PDF's according to products, adds internal notes, manages shipping data, makes monthly reports developed with Python. Maintained it's legacy code.
- ShippingRateCalculator is an order weight and shipping processor tool, an adjustment to Shipzon project. Takes order address and closest warehouse/production center and calculates the closest cargo option and checks and fixes Shipzon's wrong weight data according to account manager sheets. Maintained & developed rest.

Frontend Developer (Freelance)

Xena Vision

Developed a frontend only website for Xena Vision.

· Link: https://github.com/berkpeker2707/xena_vision_frontend

SKILLS

REST API HTML

JavaScript TypeScript

CSS

Google App Script NodeJS

Express Electron React

React Native Expo Redux

Redux Toolkit Python Jest Git

Heroku Vercel Microsoft Azure

Docker Redis Mongoose

MongoDB Atlas Elasticsearch

NoSQL MySQL

PERSONAL PROJECTS

habitune

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.thelittleteaclipper.habitune

Social habit application

WAIPE

∂ https://github.com/berkpeker2707/WAIPE
Social media application for pets.

muLa

https://github.com/berkpeker2707/muLa
 A dating app based on Myers-Briggs Type Indicator.

LANGUAGES

Turkish	Native
English	Proficient
German	Beginner

EXPERIENCE

Intern

Digital Partners

= 04/2019 - 05/2019

istanbul, Turkey

Worked on front-end development by using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript. Designed web applications ac- cording to customers' demands.

- Created popup pages as return after POST request using Javascript, HTML and CSS.
- Developed noUiSlider and filtered the returned data according to defined
- Implemented Facebook login and LinkedIn login features by using developer tools.
- Reduced performance issues on web application.
- Designed TinyPNG app for reducing images weight on site with minimal quality reduction by us- ing javascript and ajax.
- Created a product displaying website and its mailing system design by using bootstrap, jquery.
- Debugged already existed projects and added media queries for mobile phones.

Intern

Cybersoft

= 07/2017 - 09/2017

istanbul, Turkey

Worked on Machine Learning Technologies for by using Java, Apache Spark. Increased the application efficiency and implemented Grubbs Test, Mahalanobis distance data elimination techniques.

- Used k-value for each supervised data group and used regression to find better grouped data sets which helped to reduce insufficient, nosiy data.
- Used Grubbs Test for detection of outlier data via using Apache Spark's library, either one-sided min, one-sided max or two-sided outlier.
- Used Mahalanobis distance measurement, calculated centroid (arithmetic mean). According to euclidian distance, categorised whether the data is outlier or not.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degrees in Software Engineering

Bahcesehir Unversity

CLUB & ASSOCIATION MEMBERSHIPS

Bahcesehir Unversity - Software and Informatics Club Membership (2016 -2017)

AIESEC Istanbul Memberships (2015 -2017)